A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Staff Subject Files, Kilolo Kijakazi FA1848
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grant Working Files and Ford Foundation Initiatives, 1987-2014; 1; 37.3 Cubic Feet
  - Reports, Publications, and Correspondence, 1990-2014; 30
    - Howard University Reports, 2009-2010 (Box 39, Folder 372)
    - NAACP Proposal FY 2014 Request 121936, 2013-2014 (Box 40, Folder 378)
    - Dedrick Muhammad, Potential Support for NAACP, 2008-2012 (Box 40, Folder 379)
    - NAACP Working File, 2006-2012 (Box 40, Folder 380-381)
      Grant 10801047, National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, To educate high school and college students about saving, debt reduction, asset building and Social Security
    - Puerto Rico Strategies, Inc. and Center for a New Economy Working File, 2011-2013 (Box 42, Folder 402)
    - Center for a New Economy (Puerto Rico) FY 2012 (Box 42, Folder 403)
    - Corporacion del Proyecto ENLACE del Cano Martin Pena, 2006 (Box 42, Folder 404)
    - Ifetayo Cultural Arts Facility - Working Files, 2007-2009 (Box 42, Folder 405, Box 43, Folder 406)
    - California Secure Choice Retirement Savings Trust FY 2014, 2012-2014 (Box 43, Folder 407)
    - Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED) - Savings for Working Families Act (SWFA), 2007 (Box 46, Folder 429)
    - Asset Policy Direction Meeting, 2006 (Box 46, Folder 430)
    - Meeting with Gene Steuerle on Asset Policy, 2006 April 3 (Box 47, Folder 431)
    - Meeting with Bob Greenstein on Asset Policy, 2006 April 3 (Box 47, Folder 432)
    - Asset Building Federal Policy, 2006 (Box 47, Folder 433)
    - State Assets Policy Conference: Inclusion in Asset Building Policies at the State and Federal Levels, 2006 June 28-30 (Box 47, Folder 434-435)
    - America Saving for Personal Investment, Retirement, and Education (ASPIRE) Act of 2005, 2006 (Box 47, Folder 436)
    - New America Foundation - Claudie Kiti Bustamante, 2006 (Box 47, Folder 437)
    - Rapid Response Kitchen Cabinet for Policy - Third Meeting, 2005 (Box 47, Folder 438)
    - Ten Big Ideas for a New America, New America Foundation, 2006 December (Box 47, Folder 439)
    - The Assets Agenda 2011: Policy Options to Promote Savings and Asset Development, New America Foundation, 2010 September (Box 47, Folder 440)
    - Child Savings Accounts: A Primer, Global Assets Project, New America Foundation, 2008 July (Box 47, Folder 441)
    - Oklahoma Mortgage Lending Patterns: A Research Study, Prepared by Angela M. Gobar, Ph. D for the Howard University Center on Race and Wealth, Washington, DC, Submitted to Oklahoma Asset Building Partnership and Practice Initiative, 2011 October (Box 47, Folder 442)
    - Civic Service Worldwide: The Global Service Institute Meeting, Presentation to the Ford Foundation handouts, April 21, 2005 (Box 47, Folder 443)
    - Youth Volunteerism and Civic Service in Latin America and the Caribbean: A Potential Strategy for Social and Economic Development, Background Research Paper, Center for Social Development, 2004 March (Box 47, Folder 444)
    - Inclusion in College Savings Plans: Participation and Saving in Maine's Matching Grant Program, Center for Social Development, 2006 April (Box 47, Folder 445)
    - SEED for Oklahoma Kids Implementation, Management and Research Meeting, 2001 April 13 (Box 47, Folder 446)
    - Saving for College in Maine's Matching Grant Program: Account Owner Experiences, Center for Social Development, 2006 April (Box 47, Folder 447)
    - The SEED for Oklahoma Kids Experiment: Initial Account Opening and Savings, Center for Social Development Research Report No. 10-14, 2010 (Box 47, Folder 448)
    - Lessons from SEED: A National Demonstration of Child Development Accounts, 2010 September (Box 47, Folder 449)
    - Ongoing, University of Michigan School of Social Work: Winter, Spring, 2006 (Box 48, Folder 450)
    - Center for Social Development Research Briefs, 2009-2010 (Box 48, Folder 451)
    - Hope in Concrete Form: The Downpayments on the American Dream Policy Demonstration, Conception, Contributions, Challenges and Consequences, 2005 January (Box 48, Folder 452)
    - Building Assets: A Report on the Asset-Development and IDA Field, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), 2001 December (Box 48, Folder 453)
    - Savings and Asset Accumulation in Individual Development Accounts, Downpayments on the American Dream Policy Demonstration, A National Demonstration of Individual Development Accounts, Center for Social Development, 2001 February (Box 48, Folder 454)
    - Children and Youth Services Review: Special Issue, Child Development Accounts: Theory, Evidence, and Policy Potential, Volume 32, Issue 11, 2010 November (Box 48, Folder 455)
    - Children's Savings Accounts and the Save and Invest Economy, Carl Rist and Robert Friedman with Mike Knight, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), 2010 November (Box 48, Folder 456)
    - Assets and Opportunities Scorecard, Executive Summary, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), 2009-2010 (Box 48, Folder 457)
    - Guide to the Assets and Opportunity Scorecard, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), 2007-2008 (Box 48, Folder 458)
    - Assets and Opportunity Scorecard: Financial Security Across the States, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), 2005 (Box 48, Folder 459)
    - State Asset Development Report Card: Benchmarking Asset Development in Fighting Poverty, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), 2002 (Box 48, Folder 460)
    - The Road to Yes: How to Build Public Support for Government Action to Help People Achieve Financial Security, undated (Box 48, Folder 461)
    - Building Assets: Self Employment for Welfare Recipients: Overview of the Findings from the Self Employment Investment Demonstration (SEID), Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), undated (Box 48, Folder 462)
    - Children's Development Accounts: A State Policy Sourcebook, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), 2009 August (Box 49, Folder 463)
    - Federal Individual Development Account Briefing Book: How IDAs Affect Eligibility for Federal Programs, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), 2002 (Box 49, Folder 464)
    - From Piggy Banks to Prosperity: A Guide to Implementing Children's Development Accounts, SEED, 2008 September (Box 49, Folder 465)
    - Special Report: Promoting Economic Security for Working Families, State Asset-Building Initiatives, Heather McCulloch, 2005 July (Box 49, Folder 466)
    - Asset Development Policy: The New Opportunity, Larry W. Beeferman, Asset Development Institute, 2001 October (Box 49, Folder 467)
    - Summary: Hidden in Plain Sight: A Look at the 335 Billion Federal-Asset Building Budget, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), 2004 (Box 49, Folder 468)
    - Assets and Opportunity: Special Report, Net Worth, Wealth Inequality and Homeownership During the Bubble Years, Corporation for Economic Development (CFED), 2008 September (Box 49, Folder 469)
    - The Assets Movement at Its Moment: 2010 Assets Learning Conference, Washington, D.C. Conference Program, Corporation for Economic Development (CFED) (Box 49, Folder 470)
    - Upside Down: The 400 Billion Federal Asset-Building Budget, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED) and The Annie E. Casey Foundation, 2010 (Box 49, Folder 471)
    - Return on Investment? Getting More From Federal Asset-Building Policies, Lillian Woo and David Buchholz, Corporation for Economic Development (CFED) and CFED Digests, 2007 (Box 49, Folder 472)
    - 2009 Conference on Children and Youth Savings Conference Program, Brooklyn, New York, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), 2009 June 14-16 (Box 49, Folder 473)
    - Saving for Education, Entrepreneurship, and Downpayment (SEED) Initiative - Background Information, 2005 (Box 49, Folder 474)
    - Demonstrating Opportunity: A Compendium of Practical Experience and Lessons Learned from the SEED Initiative, 2010 (Box 49, Folder 475)
    - Building Public Support for Government Action to Help People Achieve Financial Independence: Message Briefing, undated (Box 49, Folder 476)
    - The Aspen Institute Financial Security Summit: Rebuilding Household Balance Sheets, Rapporteur's Report by Colby Farber, 2012 July 10-13 (Box 49, Folder 477)
    - Building Economic Security Over a Lifetime, Message Manual, Hattaway Communications, 2013 January (Box 49, Folder 478)
    - Assets and Opportunity Institute, San Francisco, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), 2007 September 24-25 (Box 50, Folder 479)
    - SEED Monthly Publication, Corporation for Enterprise Development (CFED), 2005-2010 (Box 50, Folder 480)
    - Savings and Conditional Cash Transfers (CCTs): A Global Colloquium at the Ford Foundation - Notes and Reports, 2010 November 8-9 (Box 50, Folder 481)
    - Building Economic Security Over a Lifetime (BESOL) Initiative in United States, South Africa, and Latin America FY 2011, 2011-2012 (Box 50, Folder 482)
    - Collaboration with Federal Agencies - Meeting with Hilary Duke at Employee Benefits Security Administration, Department of Labor, 2011-2013 (Box 50, Folder 483)
    - Collaboration with Federal Agencies - Meeting with Health and Human Services Assistant Secretary, 2009-2012 (Box 50, Folder 484)
    - Collaboration with Federal Agencies - Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), 2012 (Box 50, Folder 485)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Kindergarten to College Symposium, San Francisco, California, 2012 December 11-12 (Box 50, Folder 486)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Atlantic Philanthropies, 2009-2013 (Box 51, Folder 487)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Atlantic Philanthropies - Proposed Bipartisan Commission, 2009-2010 (Box 51, Folder 488)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Social Security Works: Strengthen Social Security Campaign, 2010 (Box 51, Folder 489)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Mott and Ford Foundations' Children's Savings Accounts Strategy Session, 2014 March 27-28 (Box 51, Folder 490-491)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Annie E. Casey, 2007-2013 (Box 52, Folder 492)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Citibank - Meeting with Sandy Fernandez, 2011-2012 (Box 52, Folder 493)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Kellogg, 2007-2013 (Box 52, Folder 494)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Mott Foundation Work on Coalition Building - State Assets Coalition Cluster Convening, 2009-2013 (Box 52, Folder 495)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Open Society Contacts, undated (Box 52, Folder 496)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Meeting with Erin Currier at Pew Charitable Trusts, 2011-2012 (Box 52, Folder 497)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Funders Meeting, Public Sector Retirement Benefits, Arnold Foundation and Pew Charitable Trusts, 2013 (Box 52, Folder 498)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Rockefeller Foundation Grants (Value of Social Security), 2007-2009 (Box 52, Folder 499)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - TIAA-CREF, Stephanie Bell-Rose, 2011-2012 (Box 52, Folder 500)
    - Collaboration with Foundations - Z. Smith Reynolds and Mary Fant Donnan - Racial Wealth Gap, 2010 (Box 52, Folder 501)
    - Asset Funders Network (AFN) Meetings, 2005-2013 (Box 53, Folder 502-504)
    - NYC Department of Consumer Affairs, Office of Financial Empowerment, undated; CD (Box 53)
    - Philanthropy New York, Inc.: FY 2014 Request 121935 (Box 53, Folder 505)
    - Philanthropy New York, Inc.: FY 2011 Request 118608, 2011-2012 (Box 54, Folder 506)
    - Philanthropy New York, Inc.: Working File 115026, 2011-2013 (Box 54, Folder 507)
    - Asset Funders Network: 2010 Spring Meeting, Taking Two Steps Forward, Chicago, 2010 May 5-6 (Box 54, Folder 508)
    - Philanthropy New York, Inc. (Formerly New York Regional Grantmakers Associations NYRAG): Working File, 2009 (Box 54, Folder 509)
    - Philanthropy New York, Inc. (Formerly New York Regional Grantmakers Associations NYRAG): Asset Funders Working File, 2007 (Box 54, Folder 510)
    - Center on Federal Financial Institutions (COFFI) - Working File, 2005-2008 (Box 56, Folder 538)
      Center on Federal Financial Institutions (10751045), 2007 July 01-2007 December 31
      To educate workers and retired citizens about their rights and responsibilities with regard to pension plans
    - Center on Federal Financial Institutions (COFFI) - Douglas Elliott (Works on Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC)), 2005-2007 (Box 56, Folder 539)
    - Center on Federal Financial Institutions (COFFI) - Working File Grant 1075-1045-0, 2008-2009 (Box 56, Folder 540)
      Grant Number: 10751045
      Grant Date: 2007 July 01-2007 December 31
      Grant Purpose: To educate workers and retired citizens about their rights and responsibilities with regard to pension plans
      Grant Amount: 45,500.00; 45,500.00
    - Columbia University School of Social Work, New York State Earned Income Tax Credit - Working File, 2009-2012 (Box 56, Folder 541, Box 57, Folder 542)
    - Columbia University School of Social Work, New York State Earned Income Tax Credit - Articles and Reports, 1998-2006 (Box 57, Folder 543)
    - Center on Budget and Policy Priorities (CBPP) - Papers on Fatherhood, 1998 (Box 57, Folder 544)
    - The Opportunity Agenda: Working File, 2008 (Box 57, Folder 545)
    - Closing the Racial Wealth Gap, Strategic Communications, Webinar for Experts of Color, 2007 (Box 57, Folder 546)
    - Closing the Racial Wealth Gap, Meeting with Alan Jenkins about Developing a Message for Experts of Color Convening, 2006-2008 (Box 57, Folder 547)
    - Urban Institute Summer Academy Working Files, 2007-2012 (Box 58, Folder 548-552)
      Grant 1080-0360
    - Women's Self-Employment Project (WSEP) - Dissolution and Ford Response, 2004-2008 (Box 58, Folder 553)
    - Women's Self-Employment Project (WSEP) - Grant Status Reports, 1998-2005 (Box 59, Folder 554)
    - Women's Self-Employment Project (WSEP) - Departure of Wanda White and Appearance of Financial Problems, 2004-2005 (Box 59, Folder 555)
    - University of Kansas - Child Saving Accounts, SEED Research Grant Proposal, 2009-2014 (Box 66, Folder 589-591)
    - Realize Consulting - Working File - Calls, 2013-2014 (Box 70, Folder 628)
    - Realize Consulting - Working File - Grant Requests, 2011-2013 (Box 70, Folder 629)
    - Realize Consulting - Working Files, 2006-2013 (Box 70, Folder 630, Box 71, Folder 631-636)
      Realize Consulting Group (10600545), 2008 March 01-2010 February 28
      To provide technical assistance to organizations implementing the Savings for Education, Entrepreneurship and Downpayment (SEED) demonstration and evaluation project
    - New America Foundation - Children's Savings Accounts: Lessons from the United Kingdom's Child Trust Fund Program and Implications for Policy in the United States Seminar, 2010 April 27 (Box 71, Folder 637)
    - The College Savings Initiative: Discussion at the Ford Foundation, 2009 October 20 (Box 71, Folder 638)
    - SEED 2: Adding an Experimental Site, 2003 July (Box 71, Folder 639)
    - Saving for Education, Entrepreneurship, and Downpayment (SEED) Policy and Practice Initiative, Launch Meeting, Washington, D.C., 2003 October 27-29 (Box 71, Folder 640)
    - University of California, Los Angeles, Asian American Studies Center (AASC) - Meeting with Ford Foundation Financial Assets Unit, 2014 March 17 (Box 76, Folder 682)
    - University of California, Los Angeles, Asian American Studies Center (AASC) - Working Files, 2006-2014 (Box 76, Folder 683-686, Box 77, Folder 687)
    - University of Arkansas - Individual Development Accounts (IDA) Research - Articles, 2000-2007 (Box 77, Folder 688)
    - University of Arkansas - Individual Development Accounts (IDA) Policy, Practice, and Research Summit, Empowering Change, 2012 April 25-27 (Box 77, Folder 689)
      Grant 01300178
      To assess the long-term retention of assets and the well-being of participants in individual development account programs in Arkansas and New Mexico
    - Aint I A Person With Apologies to Sojourner Truth, Another America At Last Productions, Directed by Keith M. Kilty, undated; DVD (Box 77)
    - University of Arkansas - Individual Development Accounts (IDA) in Arizona and New Mexico - Working Files, 2006-2013 (Box 77, Folder 690-693, Box 78, Folder 694-696)
      Grants 01300178 and 11000698 and 10600861
    - Meeting on Retirement Investment Advice, Phyllis Borzi, Alicia Munnell, 2014 March 13 (Box 80, Folder 715)
    - Testimony Before the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (ERISA) Advisory Council on Disparities for Women and Minorities in Retirement, 2011-2013 (Box 80, Folder 716)
    - Boston College, Center for Retirement Research Working Files, 2010-2014 (Box 80, Folder 717-718)
    - Brandeis University, Institute on Assets and Social Policy Working Files, 2007-2014 (Box 80, Folder 719-720, Box 81, Folder 721-723)
    - Center on Budget and Policy Priorities (CBPP) Working Files, 2003-2013 (Box 81, Folder 724-727)
      Center on Budget and Policy Priorities (10700849), 2007 September 01-2010 December 31
      To conduct research and policy analysis on the impact of proposed Social Security reforms on the United States federal budget
    - Center on Budget and Policy Priorities (CBPP) State Fiscal Analysis Initiative (SFAI) State Policy Diverse Fellows Program, 2008-2009 (Box 81, Folder 728)
    - Center for Community Change - The Power of Many: 40 Years of the Center for Community Change, 2008 (Box 81, Folder 729)
    - Center for Community Change - Working Files, 2005-2014 (Box 82, Folder 730-732)
      Grant Number 11201545
    - National Council of La Raza (NCLR) - Publications, 2004-2006 (Box 85, Folder 756)
    - National Council of La Raza (NCLR) - Working Files, 2004-2012 (Box 85, Folder 757-758, Box 86, Folder 759-762)
      Grant Numbers 1120-1967 and 10200281, 2001 October 01-2010 April 30
      Core support for the Economic Mobility Initiative to develop and implement a strategy to enhance the financial security and economic mobility of Latino families in the United States
    - National Council of La Raza (NCLR) - Collaborative Grant with Human Rights, 2010-2013 (Box 86, Folder 763)
    - New America - Working Files, 2003-2014 (Box 86, Folder 764-769, Box 87, Folder 770-772)
      New America Foundation (10301041), 2003 May 01-2011 April 30
      Core support for the Asset Building Program to promote savings and asset-building policies and programs for low- and moderate-income Americans
      New America Foundation (10401405), 2004 September 20-2010 November 30
      To develop a federal policy agenda and national communications strategy for promoting asset building through the establishment of publicly supported children's savings accounts
    - America Saving for Personal Investment, Retirement, and Education (ASPIRE) Press Conference, People for People Site Visit, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 2004-2005 (Box 87, Folder 773)
    - The Opportunity Agenda - Economic Recovery and Equal Opportunity in the Public Discourse, An Analysis of Media Content and Public Opinion, 2010 (Box 92, Folder 811)
    - The Opportunity Agenda - Talking Human Rights in the United States: A Communications Toolkit, 2010 (Box 92, Folder 812)
    - The Opportunity Agenda - Reproductive Justice: Opinion Research with Core Audiences and Policymakers, 2011 (Box 92, Folder 813)